Shiqi.
十七郎
Through my secret investigation, I didn't notice anything strange
我暗中追查下来
in Lord Xin's Residence.
并没有什么异样
The usage of vegetable oil, sesame oil,
特别是菜油 麻油
firewood and coal
干柴 木炭等物
doesn't differ much from the usual usage.
和往日的用量
I also checked Lord Xin's account
而且我也查了历年历月
with the oil and coal suppliers
信王府在油铺
in previous years
还有炭铺等处的账目
and compared it with the kitchen and woodshed.
对着厨房 还有柴房
Everything seems normal.
都没有什么不对
If there was no fuel for combustion,
这要说没有助燃之物
why would the fire be so strong?
怎么会烧成那样
This is so strange.
这也太奇怪了
Exactly.
是啊
I also investigated the servants in the residence.
我也查了府中的仆役
However,
查来查去
I still didn't find any clue.
也没有发现
Shiqi.
十七郎
See what Wan'niang brought you.
看婉娘给你带什么来了
Nanny, why are you here?
奶娘 您怎么来了
Next time, send someone to inform me.
你下次要来
I'll go over.
我过去便是
It's just a short distance.
这几步路啊
I can still walk.
我还走得动
Wan'niang purposely went to Xiangji Temple
婉娘特意去香积寺啊
and requested the Heart Sutra
求了一部住持大师
which the abbot copied by hand.
亲手抄写的心经
It is believed
据说
that offering the Heart Sutra before ancestral tablets
供在往生人的牌位前
is the best way to accumulate blessings
最是能积福消业
and eliminate karma.
积攒功德
We are here to give it to you
今日特意送来
so that you can offer it in front of Madam Liu's tablet.
让你供在刘娘娘灵前
Thank you.
谢谢
Nanny.
奶娘
Let me put it for you.
我帮您插吧
Beware of the fire.
您小心火烛烫到手
What happened?
怎么了
I wasn't paying attention just now.
刚刚我没留神
I accidentally burnt a hole in the embroidered portrait.
不小心将绣像烫了个洞
What should I do?
这可怎么办呀
This is all my fault.
这可真是我的罪过呀
It's all right.
没事
It's just a tiny hole.
一个小孔洞而已
Miss Gu, you don't have to blame yourself.
顾小姐不必自责
However, this is Madam Liu's portrait.
这可是刘娘娘的绣像
It's all my fault for being careless.
都怪我不谨慎
Miss.
小姐
Since you burnt a hole in the embroidery,
既然烫坏了一个小洞
why don't you fix it?
把它补上不就行了
You are such a nimble-fingered person.
你那么心灵手巧
Last time, I accidentally dirtied
上次那柄白纨扇
the white silk fan.
被我不小心弄脏了
Then, you embroidered a butterfly on it.
你就在上面
It was so exquisite.
可精致可美了
The stain couldn't be seen at all.
一点都看不出来
Your Highness,
殿下
please allow me to take the portrait down
就让我把绣像请下来
and fix the embroidery.
好好织补一番吧
Shiqi,
十七郎啊
hurry up and take it down.
你快点把它摘下来
Let Wan'niang embroider it here.
让婉娘在这儿织补了
Miss Gu, sorry to have troubled you.
那就麻烦顾小姐了
Your Highness, why did you say so?
殿下何出此言
I'm just mending what I've done.
婉娘只是亡羊补牢罢了
Your Highness.
殿下
General Han, it's time to take your medicine.
韩将军 该喝药了
Thank you, Your Highness.
谢殿下
Is your injury
韩将军身上的伤
getting better?
好些了吗
It's a lot better now.
好多了
To be honest,
其实
from the moment I rescued Your Highness,
自从救出殿下那一刻呀
I felt my injury
我便觉得这些伤
was not serious at all.
早就无碍了
I also didn't expect
我也没想到
that I would see you again.
还能再见到韩将军
When I was
当时
taken captive by Sun Jing,
我被孙靖掳去的时候
I thought
我就想
I must die with integrity if I really had to.
死 也要死得有气节
I must not
不能丢了
bring disgrace to the Li's family.
我们李家子弟的脸面
I never thought that I would be rescued.
没想到还能获救
After we have rescued you,
那日救下太孙后
we were in a hopeless dilemma.
我们走投无路
Fortunately, Lord Qin's subordinates
幸得溱王手下
found us and informed Consort Xiao.
寻到并告知萧妃娘娘
Her Highness allowed us to stay here for a few days.
娘娘让我们在这里暂住些时日
The situation in the capital is complicated.
京中形势复杂
The Cui family relied on their military power
崔家挟兵权自重
just like how Sun Jing used to be.
威势一如之前的孙靖
Although His Majesty is your uncle,
陛下虽是太孙的叔父
there are also people with vile characters around him.
但身边却也有小人
Lord Xin and Lord Qi
信王 齐王
are the current emperor's own sons.
都是今上的亲生儿子
How they would see you
他们会如何看待殿下
is still unclear.
还都暧昧未明
Humans are born intrinsically with a good and similar nature.
人之初 性本善
However, their natures will change based on what they learn.
性相近 习相远
If a child does not receive proper education, his good nature will change.
苟不教 性乃迁
The way to educate a child well is through total commitment and devotion.
教之道 贵以专
Mencius' mother shifted three times to find the best place to bring up her son.
昔孟母 择邻处
Once Mencius was absent from school, she cut the cloth she was knitting.
子不学 断机杼
Have you got used to living here?
此处可还住得惯
In the private school,
私塾里
many children are coming in and out.
每日进出的孩子多
The fact that we are hiding here
咱们藏在这里呀
won't be noticeable.
不会引人注意
This place is good.
这里很好
When I heard the sound of reading yesterday,
昨日听到读书声
I felt at ease.
觉得甚是心安
I've been hearing about private schools.
一直听说私塾
Now that I'm here,
如今到了这里也才知道
I finally know what a private school looks like.
私塾原来是这样啊
It is good that Your Highness
殿下喜欢读书
likes studying.
这是好事
I want to study more and learn more skills
我想多读书 多学本事
so that my mother will feel happy
这样母妃见到我的时候
when she sees me.
才会觉得欢喜
I've grown taller.
我比之前长高了
I've also learned more knowledge compared to the past.
也要比之前
It's all my fault for being careless.
都怪我不谨慎
This type of silk is highly flammable.
这种丝绸最是易燃
Just a short contact with the incense stick could cause a hole.
香头碰上去
Even the golden threads beneath were damaged.
连里面的金线都烧断了
Authentic golden threads like this would shrink to small beads
这种真金线
when they are burnt and broken.
就缩成小小一颗
They are not like silk threads
又不像丝线
that can be connected again.
可以重新接起来
The entire thread has to be removed to redo the embroidery.
只能整根抽出来重新绣
No wonder you asked me to get this type of golden thread.
怪不得你让我命人
I didn't know a small bundle like this could weigh this much.
没想到小小的一捆
The golden threads taken from the Department of Clothing
司衣处取来的金线
have premium quality.
乃是上上好的金线
That is why they weigh so much.
自然分量十足
Speaking of this,
说起来
a few years ago, the late emperor
先帝几年前曾下令
banned the commoners from doing embroidery using golden threads.
天下人禁穿绣金衣
Everyone didn't dare to break the law.
诸人自然不敢违令
Hence, they pasted
所以
gold foil
他们就把金箔
on the silk.
贴在丝绸上
These are not considered embroidery using golden threads.
这些就不算绣金衣
Instead, these are gilded clothes,
而是贴金衣
so, it wasn't against the law.
也不算违令了
In recent years, it has been quite popular in the capital.
近几年来
Your Highness.
殿下
You said
你刚说
this type of silk is highly flammable.
这种丝绸最是易燃
Yes.
是呀
If a lot of such silk were put together,
那若是很多很多丝绸
wouldn't they be
放在一起
as flammable
岂不是
as the oil chamber?
犹如油房一般易燃
Of course.
那是自然
I heard that at silk fabric shops in the capital, there are high walls
我听说
and large tanks filled with water outside the storeroom
都砌了高墙
just in case their neighboring shops catch fire.
就怕左邻右舍走水了
Otherwise, everything would be burned
那可真就付之一炬
and nothing could be retrieved.
抢都抢不回来了
Your Highness, are you all right?
殿下 你怎么了
Just now, you also said
你刚还说
that people in the capital usually wear gilded clothes
京都里都穿贴金衣
and they paste gold foils on the fabric.
都在丝绸上贴金
Yes.
对啊
Although it's only a thin film,
虽然只是薄薄一层金箔
having it on the clothes gives it a brilliant look.
但贴上去光华灿烂
It looks really nice.
十分好看呢
When a real golden thread catches fire,
真金线一碰到火
it shrinks to a small size.
就会缩小成一颗
When a real gold film catches fire,
那么真金箔
the same happens.
同样是这个道理
Your Highness, what are you thinking?
殿下 你在想什么
Nothing.
没什么
Miss Gu.
顾小姐
I just remembered that I need to
我突然想起一桩要紧事
tell Pei Yuan something important.
要与裴源说
Please excuse me.
先告辞了
Shiqi.
十七郎
Why are there some golden beads
从信王府后院
in the soil taken from the backyard of Lord Xin's Residence?
挖出来的泥土
Go and check
去查一查
whether the people in Lord Xin's Residence
信王府里
bought gilded silk in bulk recently.
大量采办贴金绸缎
Gilded silk?
贴金绸缎
Also,
还有
investigate the confidants
信王那些亲信们
of Lord Xin.
也都给我查一查
Check whether they have also purchased gilded silk.
有没有同样采办
All right.
好
Young Master.
公子
A news from the secret agent.
密探来报
Lieutenant He, with only a troop of men,
校尉只带了一队人马
is coming in Xichang's direction.
往西长京这边来了
Is she coming to the capital?
她要进京
She doesn't look like she plans to.
看着也不像
They are moving quite slowly.
行得很慢
It's as if she's waiting
倒像是
for someone.
在等什么
She's probably waiting for Li Ni.
她是在等李嶷吧
Her infatuation for Li Ni
她一片痴心
will most probably be left unanswered.
李嶷怕是要辜负了
Li Ni is such a pedantic person.
李嶷这个人
At this point,
事到如今
he still doesn't dare to tell Ying
也不敢对阿萤说一句
that he wants to marry her.
我想娶你
As for Lord Xin and Lord Qi,
信王 齐王
who do they think they are?
又是个什么东西
How dare they imagine marrying Ying?
也敢肖想阿萤
Young Master.
公子
Shall we give them a lesson?
要不要出手
There's no need to give the game away.
不必打草惊蛇
Yes.
是
It's good that Ying is coming out
阿萤既然从泺阳出来
from Luoyang.
也是好事
At least she's no longer with the Cui Army.
起码脱离了
Otherwise,
否则
it will be difficult for us to get in on the ground.
我们难以下手
I have sent people to follow Lieutenant He secretly.
已经派了人
Pick a good time
选一个好的时机
and set up the maze secretly.
再偷偷布下迷阵
Do not let Cui Yi realise.
不能让崔倚轻易察觉
Understand.
明白
Everything is clear now.
全部都查清楚了
Indeed, Lord Xin wanted to harm Consort Xin.
确实就是信王想害王妃
He ordered people to send numerous gilded silk
信王以裁衣为由
to Consort Xin's room for the reason of making clothes.
命人将大量的贴金绸缎
Then, fire was set.
纵火助燃
Furthermore, on the night of the fire,
而且走水的那天晚上
they also delayed the rescue process on purpose.
也是他们故意耽搁救火
One of them admitted that
其中还有一人招供说
they drugged
他们在王妃
the food for Consort Xin
还有丫鬟仆役的食物中
and her servants.
投下了迷药
Therefore,
所以那天晚上
none of them woke up that night.
所有人都没有醒来
All of them were burned to death.
全部被活活地烧死灭口
Li Jun!
李峻
How could he be so vicious?
他怎能如此狠毒
Consort Xin was married to him for many years.
大嫂跟了他这么多年
They had been through difficult times together.
也算患难夫妻
Now, we have
现在虽然是
witnesses, material evidence,
人证 物证 口供
and statements,
都有了
but we still need to identify the witness
就差迷药的出处
who knows about the drugging.
还没有拘到人证
Lord Xin is indeed disappointing.
这个信王
Shiqi.
但是十七郎
Do you really plan to report him
你真的打算在陛下面前
in front of His Majesty?
告发他吗
Ever since Consort Dong passed away,
董王妃去世后
only Consort Xin cared for me.
只有大嫂关心我呵护我
She died so unjustly.
她死得如此冤屈
I must seek justice for her
我一定要在陛下面前
in front of His Majesty.
替她讨个公道
- Long Live Your Majesty!
陛下万岁万岁万万岁
Please rise.
平身
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
谢陛下
Where is Lord Qin?
溱王呢
Your Majesty,
陛下
Lord Qin said he had urgent military affairs.
溱王说有要紧军务
He left the capital early in the morning,
一早就出城了
so he could not make it to the morning meeting.
赶不及朝会
He asked me to request a day's leave from Your Majesty.
让臣给您告假
He always claims to have military affairs to handle,
成天军务军务的
as if he is the only
就好像他一个人
busy person.
有事似的
Your Majesty.
陛下
Cui Yi submits a letter
崔倚上书
stating that he is willing to marry his daughter to the prince.
愿将女儿嫁给皇子
I think
臣以为
this matter should be confirmed as soon as possible.
此事宜早早定夺
It's not good to ask Cui Yi
这 总不好去问崔倚
whether he wants to
齐王跟溱王
marry his daughter
到底要把女儿
to Lord Qi or Lord Qin.
嫁给哪一个
Your Majesty, since Lord Xin is a new widower,
陛下 信王新鳏
he could marry Miss Cui as well.
信王也可以迎娶崔氏
You have a point.
卿说得有道理啊
Your Majesty.
陛下
Consort Xin has just passed away
信王妃刚刚殒了
not long ago.
不多时日
I do not have the intention to remarry.
儿臣真的没有心思续弦
Lord Xin
信王真是
is indeed a man with affection and loyalty.
有情有义之人哪
Why would a man with affection and loyalty
有情有义之人
plot a murder against his own wife
又怎会行谋害结发之妻
and do something extremely tragic?
灭绝人伦之事呢
Your Majesty.
陛下
Lord Xin first drugged
信王先是给信王妃
Consort Xin and her servants.
和伺候王妃的人
Then, he placed bundles of silk that are highly flammable in her room
又在王妃屋子里
and set the room on fire, making it like an accident.
故意纵火
This caused the death of Consort Xin
活活烧死了信王妃
and everyone staying there.
和满院子的人
This is an unfounded accusation!
你血口喷人
Li Ni! What are you talking about?
李嶷 你胡说什么
Your Majesty.
陛下
I have all the witnesses and evidence.
人证 物证一应俱全
I left the capital early in the morning to investigate this matter.
儿臣今日一早出城
The person who sent the silk
运送绸缎入府的人
and Lord Xin's confidants who did the drugging
和下迷药的信王亲信
have been captured by me.
皆已被我捉拿
The testimony of the confidants of Lord Xin as well as the evidence
信王亲信数人的口供
have been sent to Dali Temple.
已经一起送往了大理寺
Your Majesty.
陛下
He is making an unfounded accusation!
他血口喷人哪
I didn't do it!
儿臣没有
I really didn't do any of these!
儿臣真的没有
Father, please seek justice for me!
父皇 请为我做主啊
Those witnesses
那些人证
are all serving in your residence.
都是你府中之人
Many of them were assigned by His Majesty
不少是父皇指派
and have been with you since you were young.
从小跟着你的人
Jun.
峻儿
Jun!
峻儿啊
Father!
父皇 父皇
I really didn't do it!
儿臣真的没有啊
Why did you do such actions?
你为什么要做出
Why?
为什么
Someone set me up!
儿臣是遭人陷害啊
Father!
父皇
Please seek justice for me!
你要为我做主啊
Consort Xin
信王妃
was such a good child with filial piety!
多么孝顺的一个孩子啊
Someone set me up!
儿臣是遭人陷害啊
Father!
父皇
Please seek justice for me!
你要为我做主
Do you think he could bribe so many people to set you up?
他能买通那么多人
Most of them
其中还有那么多人
are even your confidants!
都是你的心腹
Do you think I'm stupid?
你以为父皇傻呀
Your Majesty.
陛下
Lord Xin's action of murdering his own wife
信王此行悖逆人伦
is totally against humanity.
谋害结发妻子之事
Please give him a serious punishment.
请陛下严惩
Father.
父皇
Take this disobedient son out.
把这个逆子拖下去
Lock him up in his residence.
关在信王府里
He shall not leave the residence.
不许出府门半步
Let him chant sutras
让他日日夜夜
and pray for Consort Xin every day
为信王妃念经祈福
to eliminate his karma.
消除他做的业债
Father!
父皇 父皇 父皇
I didn't do it!
儿臣没有啊
I didn't!
儿臣没有
Please seek justice for me!
你要为儿臣做主
I really didn't do it!
儿臣真的没有
Fa... Father!
父 父皇
Father!
父皇 父皇
Father! I really didn't do it!
父皇 儿臣没有啊
I didn't!
儿臣没有
Please seek justice for me!
你要为儿臣做主
Father! I really didn't do it!
父皇 儿臣真的没有
Father!
父皇
One day of married life breeds days of enduring affection.
一日夫妻百日恩
I never thought that Li Jun
我万万没有想到
would murder his wife.
大哥竟然能对嫂子
Fights between husband and wife and fights between brothers for property
夫妻打架
are not uncommon in my hometown.
在我们乡下也没少见过
I didn't expect that someone in the capital
谁知道在这京城
would murder
有人竟然会为了
his own wife
争权夺势
to fight for power and position.
杀了自己的婆娘
How inhuman!
也太不是东西了吧
When Consort Xin first got married,
嫂子刚嫁过来时
I was the most unwelcome person in the residence.
王府里
She knew that I lost my mother since young,
她知道我自幼丧母
so she always treated me well.
一直对我很好
How could Li Jun
如此心地善良的一个人
kill a kind person like her?
大哥也能下得了手
Before I came to Xichang,
来西长京之前
I thought this was a lively and happening place.
还想着这京都热闹
I wanted to enrich my experience.
好多见见世面
If I had known that I would experience these incidents,
谁知见了这么多事情
I wouldn't have come.
还不如不来呢
Now, I miss
现在好怀念
the mound at Laolan Pass.
牢兰关那个破土堆啊
At that time,
那个时候
we suffered
咱们兄弟们
so much.
整天苦哈哈的
We didn't have much money.
也没什么钱
We even had to fight with one another
就连吃口那个白面饼子
just to get a bite of the white bread,
大家都要争来抢去的
but our life was so happy.
可日子过得快活呀
Yes.
是啊
Those days,
那个时候
we were really happy.
真心快活
Mister Shiqi.
十七郎
People here in the capital are so unpredictable.
这京都人心叵测
You once said
你说过
that we would go back to Laolan Pass one day.
将来咱们要回牢兰关
When will we be going back?
咱们什么时候回去呀
There are things unsettled yet.
还有事情没了
When I settle them one by one,
待一一了之
we shall go back.
咱们便回去
We won't need to care about
再也不用理会
the intrigues in this capital.
这京都中的钩心斗角了
Let's go.
走吧
(Your Highness, as time goes by,)
也许过段时间
(perhaps you would realise)
殿下就会明白
to Laolan Pass
做十七郎
as you wish
就可以回到牢兰关
As Lord Qin, you cannot escape
而是溱王殿下
your role as the crown prince.
不能不做东宫太子
Mister Shiqi, Taozi sent a letter
十七郎 桃子传信来
stating that Miss Cui is waiting to meet you at Wonderland.
说崔小姐等着
Can you submit a report
你能直接上疏
to the emperor and marry me?
嫁与我吗
Shiqi.
十七郎
Don't you understand?
你还看不明白吗
You shall be the crown prince
我跟东宫之位
in order to marry me,
要么你都要
otherwise,
否则
you are left with nothing.
你一样都得不到的
Can't you trust me?
你就不能相信我
Can you stop forcing me and give me some time?
不再逼我 给我一点时间吗
Why are you deceiving yourself and others?
你又何必自欺欺人呢
Then why did you come and meet me?
那你为什么要来见我
Indeed.
是
Everything went like what you have expected.
一切是如你所料了
What else do you want to do?
你还要怎么样呢
I'm not here to laugh at you.
我不是来看你笑话的
I know that you must be upset
我知道
seeing your loved one do something like this,
你肯定很难过
so I just want to check on you.
所以我只是想来看看你
Indeed.
是啊
He could do that
那是他结发妻子
to his wife.
他都能那样做
It's the Eastern Palace,
那是东宫
it's the position of the crown prince.
是储君之位
Power can make a person frenzied.
所以权力
That's why I don't want the position!
所以我才不要那个位子
I've known that it has been a cage since I was young.
自幼我就知道
Do you want our children
难道你要让我们的孩子
to be born
将来也生在
in this cage?
这牢笼之中吗
Right.
是
You do know that power could make a person frenzied.
权力会让人丧心病狂
With this in mind,
正因为如此
do you still want our children
你还要让我们的孩子
to fight with one another
将来因为这个位子
for this position in the future?
争得自相残杀吗
However, you are the emperor's son.
但你是天子的儿子
You are Lord Qin who recaptured two capitals.
你是收复两京的溱王
You are also the commander-in-chief of the famous Zhenxi Army.
你还是名动天下的
Don't you think
你以为此时此刻
you are currently in a cage?
你不在牢笼中吗
I don't mind making myself the bait.
我不惜以自己为饵
Can't you tell?
难道你就看不清楚吗
I don't want to fight with you.
我不想再跟你吵架了
(Don't you understand?)
难道你还看不明白吗
(You shall be the crown prince)
我跟东宫之位
(in order to marry me,)
要么你都要
(otherwise,)
否则
(you are left with nothing.)
你一样也得不到的
(Can't you trust me?)
你就不能相信我
(Can you stop forcing me and give me some time?)
不再逼我 给我一点时间吗
Come.
这儿
Would you like some pastries?
二位客官 来点唐饼
I want to eat...
我要吃
I want two of these
要两个这个
and two of these.
再要两个这个吧
Sure.
好好
Ear.
耳朵
In your opinion,
你说
why did Young Lady
这次小姐
go and meet Lord Qin alone
为什么要独自去见溱王
without bringing me with her?
不让我跟着呢
Is she hiding something from me?
她是不是有什么事情
That can't be it.
不会吧
Miss Cui treats you so well.
你们家校尉对你那么好
She won't hide any secrets from you.
她不会有事情瞒你的
Needless to say,
那是不用说的
she treats me very well.
小姐对我自然是极好的
Then why didn't she allow me to go with her?
那她为什么
Could it be because
那会不会是因为
she just wants to meet Mister Shiqi alone?
她就是想一个人
It's just like
就像我
me wanting to be
我也就想一个人
with you alone.
跟你待在一块
If both Miss Cui
如果你们家校尉
and Mister Shiqi were around,
和十七郎都在的话
wouldn't it be difficult
那我们说话
for us to talk?
岂不是很不自在
Perhaps
或许
that's what she thought.
她也是这么想的呢
When did you
你什么时候
become so honey-mouthed?
说起话来嘴这么甜了
I'm not honey-mouthed,
我没有嘴甜
I'm just telling the truth.
我就是实话实说而已
Taozi.
桃子
I want to ask you something.
我有个问题想问你
Go ahead.
你问吧
You haven't answered
上一次
the question I asked you
我在乐游原问你的问题
at Wonderland.
你还没回答我呢
Are... Are you...
你 你到底
Are you willing to?
你到底愿不愿意
You're such a fool.
傻子
If I'm not willing to,
我要是不愿意的话
will I still be sitting here
还能坐在这儿
and eating pastries with you?
跟你一起吃点心吗
That's true though.
也是 也是
Eat this.
吃吧
It's nice, right?
好吃吧
Ying.
阿萤
You're awake.
你醒了
Was it you?
是你
I got someone to help you get changed with clean clothes.
我已经找人
Ying.
阿萤
It was me
是我将你带到
who brought you here.
这个地方来的
Don't worry.
你放心
This place has beautiful scenery.
这个地方山清水秀
It's just like a paradise.
就如同世外桃源一般
Both of us
我们两个人
can live here.
一起生活在这里
We don't have to care about worldly affairs and just relax.
不问世事
There won't be
也不会再有人
people coming to disturb us.
过来打扰我们两个
Isn't that a good idea?
岂不妙哉
What drug did you give me?
你给我下了什么药
Ying.
阿萤
You shall not get angry.
你可千万不能动气
It's not good for your body.
这样对你身子不好
Your current condition is perfect.
你现在这个样子就很好
As long as you obey me,
只要你乖乖听话
I won't harm you.
我一定不会伤害你
I won't harm your father as well.
也不会去伤害你的父亲
You are a snob who colluded with Jieshuo.
你这个
You even wanted to harm my father.
还想伤害我父亲
You will be my sworn enemy!
我跟你不共戴天
Look at you.
你看你
Speak nicely.
好好说话
Why did you get angry?
怎么又生气了呢
Ying.
阿萤
What do you want to eat later?
你一会儿想吃什么
I got them to cook some of your favourite dishes.
我让人做了好些
Later, shall we have a meal together?
过一会儿
Get out of my way.
你给我滚开
Ying.
阿萤
From now on,
从今往后
we will eat together
每一天
every single day.
我们都一起吃饭
I'll be by your side all the time.
我会时时刻刻陪着你
All right?
好吗
You'll promise me,
你会答应我的
won't you?
对吧
Lord Qin.
溱王
Young Lady is missing!
我们家小姐不见了
That day, after you said that she had left,
那天你说她回去了以后
I searched along the route for fear that I went a wrong way.
我就一路找寻
I didn't see her at all even when I reached Luoyang.
直到赶回泺阳
Great General was worried
大将军很着急
and he sent people to search for her everywhere but futile.
派出人马到处找寻
That's why I came to see you with hope.
我才抱着万一的希望
Where could she have gone to?
你说她现在能去哪啊
Taozi.
桃子
How do you usually find her?
你平时怎么找到
She has been using the same herbal spices since young.
我们家小姐
I could find her with just a special ingredient,
我只要用特殊的引子
but this time,
可是这一次
it didn't work no matter how hard I tried.
无论如何我都没有办法
This means
这么说
the person who took her
劫走她的人
knows these details very well.
必然熟知这些细节
That's why he could prepare in advance
才能提前做准备
so that you wouldn't realise.
不让你发现
Then this person is...
那这个人会是
It's Liu Chengfeng.
是柳承锋
There is a vast terrain between Luoyang
泺阳与乐游原之间
and Wonderland.
地势广阔
There are many dense forests.
有无数的城廊林木
It's not difficult to hide
想要将一个人藏起来
a person.
并不是难事
If it was really Liu Chengfeng
如果真的是柳承锋
who held Miss Cui captive,
劫走崔小姐的话
it would be a big trouble.
那就糟糕了
He probably didn't stay here for too long.
他八成不敢久留
He might have left for somewhere else with Miss Cui.
应该是带着崔小姐
They wouldn't be too far away.
人一定不会被藏的太远
Why?
为什么
Ying is way too smart.
因为阿萤太过聪明了
If he wanted to go on a long journey together with her,
如果掳走她之后
it would be very difficult to not leave any clues behind.
一路上要毫无破绽
Liu Chengfeng is very obsessed with Ying.
柳承锋对阿萤执念很深
A scheming person like him
以他的心机
must have planned in advance
肯定提早在泺阳附近
and found a place near Luoyang to settle down.
布置好了安身之处
On the map,
可这舆图上
there are so many places other than Luoyang.
泺阳之外的地方
Wouldn't it
这要找到她
take a long time to locate her?
得花多长时间啊
The north.
北边
Only the northern parts.
只有北边
Since Liu Chengfeng colludes with Jieshuo,
柳承锋既与揭硕勾结
he will definitely choose somewhere
那么就一定会选一个
that he could get support from the Jieshuo rangers.
揭硕游骑
Only the northern area is possible.
那么就只有北边
The northern area is wide and scarcely inhabited.
北边地广人稀
The forest is dense.
林木茂密
Most importantly,
更重要的是
going a little up north
再往北一些
is the grassland where the Jieshuo rangers could support.
就是揭硕
Since we have narrowed down the search area
那如果
to just this part,
范围大大缩小
it will be much easier to look for her.
找她就容易多了
Let's not waste time.
事不宜迟
Let's depart now.
我们即刻出发
Without the military order, I couldn't deploy the troops now.
现在没有朝中军令
Chang'er, Bao, we shall disguise ourselves and depart first.
长耳 老鲍
- Yes.
是
Yuan.
阿源
Bring some people to the hunting ground and then catch up with us.
你带些人马去猎场
If anyone asks, tell them we are going hunting outside the city.
若有人问起
I'll do it right now.
我现在就去办
How is it?
怎么样
We have searched the hills on both sides.
这两边的山都搜过了
There's nothing strange.
没什么异样
There are high mountains and it is sparsely populated.
崇山峻岭 人烟稀少
It's not easy to find her.
不好找
Mister Shiqi.
十七郎
I have an idea.
俺倒有个法子
What is it?
什么
Last time, we used to occupy a hill and act as the lord.
原来俺们兄弟
We were also worried about the soldiers coming after us.
也担心官兵
Therefore, we would try our best to be secretive in whatever we do.
所以平时行事
However, there was
但有一件事
one thing
是无论如何
that we could never hide.
都遮掩不了的
Every person needs salt
那就是人活着
to survive.
一定得吃盐
People who sell salt
而贩盐的人
wouldn't go
是怎么都不会
deep into the forest.
走到这大山深处的
To hold Cui Lin hostage,
柳承锋要挟持崔琳
Liu Chengfeng must have many subordinates.
那他手下人一定不少
This is a remote area.
这穷乡僻壤
Salt sold at townships nearby definitely has a fixed amount.
附近乡县
Commoners
一般乡民们
cannot afford salt.
根本吃不起盐
Whenever they buy salt, they would only buy little.
他们每次换盐
They won't buy a lot.
根本不会多换
Let's investigate the townships nearby separately.
我们分头查访
Ask them whether there were any outsiders who came and bought salt
看看卖盐的地方
at a large amount.
而且数量还不少的
We could follow up from there.
就可以追查下去
All right.
行
Here.
来
Drink the medicine.
先把药喝了吧
Don't worry.
你放心
This is not poison.
这不是毒药
It's not poison,
不是毒药
but it's something that could make me feel weak
是会让我全身无力
so that you could detain me, right?
便于软禁我的药 对吗
Ying.
阿萤
I'm doing this for your own good.
我是真的为了你好
Don't be a hypocrite and tell me all this.
别跟我假惺惺地说这些
If you had cared about my feelings,
你但凡顾及我半分感受
you wouldn't have colluded with the Jieshuo people,
就不会跟揭硕人勾结
let alone harming my father.
更不会想要暗害阿爹
I didn't have a choice.
我也是逼不得已
If you had married me in the beginning,
如果你早早地嫁给我
I surely wouldn't have been in contact
我自然不会和揭硕人
with the Jieshuo people.
有任何瓜葛
I would've
我也自然会
cared for your father as well.
好好孝顺阿爹
Anyway, it's all right.
不过没关系
As long as you're willing to be with me now,
只要你现在跟我在一起
I feel satisfied.
我便心满意足了
No matter how you hit me and scold me,
不论你怎么打我 骂我
I'll enjoy it.
我都甘之如饴
If you refuse to drink it,
如果你不肯喝
I'll feed it to you.
那我喂你
This time, Youren has made great contributions.
老三这次立了大功了
We asked around in the county town.
没想到到县城一问
They said no outsiders ever came to buy salt.
根本没有外地人来买盐
However, at Huanshan County located dozens of li away,
但是隔着几十里的
someone bought
前阵子
a lot of salt not long ago.
被人买走了不少的盐
Therefore, the salt in their county
所以县上的盐
had been sent to Huanshan to be sold there.
都是被借到涣山县
Don't praise me like that.
哪当得二哥这么夸我
It was pure luck.
都是运气 运气
Look at him.
你看
The salt in Huanshan County was not necessarily bought by Liu Chengfeng.
这涣山县的盐又不见得
How could you say you are lucky?
这怎么就说自己运气好
We haven't started investigating,
这不是没查呢吗
but what if it was him?
万一是呢
- What if it wasn't him? - What if it was him?
万一不是呢
No, I said...
不是 我说不是就
Youde.
二哥
No.
不是
Listen to Mister Shiqi.
听十七郎的
Let's continue searching
我们继续分头行动
every hill separately.
搜寻各个山头
This area is about a hundred li wide.
方圆左右不过百里
Each of us
我们每个人
shall bring more people.
多带一些人马
Bao, stay in the middle as the contact point.
老鲍 居中联络
All right.
好
Let's go.
出发
- All right. - Yes!
好 是
Young Master.
公子
There seem to be strangers in villages nearby.
附近乡间似有陌生人
Our guards outside also saw hoofprints on the ground.
派在外头的哨探
Li Ni is blamed.
李嶷这个杀才
Li Ni's nose so sensitive.
鼻子比狗还灵
Now that
现在反倒
he came to me himself,
自己送上门来了
this is just right.
正好
I shall capture him
我就把他和他的狗腿子
and all his henchmen.
一网打尽
Then I shall kill them in front of Ying.
然后在阿萤面前杀了
This is the place.
就是这儿了
Mister Shiqi, what do we do?
十七郎 现在怎么办
Don't alert them first.
先不要惊动
You go and send the signal.
你去发讯号
I'll go in and check out the place.
我进去探一探
All right.
好
Ying.
阿萤
What are you looking at?
你在看什么
You seem to be deeply absorbed in it.
看得如此入神
Look.
你快看看
Look at what I've brought you.
我给你带什么过来了
I know
我知道
that you were also upset
上一次在长州
when our wedding at Changzhou
咱们的喜事被搅了局
was interrupted.
我知道你也很难过
Therefore, this time,
所以这一次
I picked a few
我就精心挑选了
wedding gowns for you.
这么多喜服
Choose the one you like.
你挑一件你喜欢的
Let's have our wedding
咱们欢欢喜喜
happily.
拜堂成亲
Liu Chengfeng.
柳承锋
Do you know
你知不知道
what you are doing?
你自己在做什么
I'm getting ready to get married to you.
我在准备
You know very well
你心里明明知道
that I won't ever marry you.
我永远都不会嫁给你的
You and I grew up together.
你我从小一起长大
I treat you
我把你当作
like an elder brother.
亲生兄长一般
To me,
在我心里
you are my elder brother.
你就是我的哥哥
Stop it!
够了
Stop saying things like this
你不要再拿这种话
to prevaricate.
来搪塞我
Your father
你父亲
has never treated me like his son.
从未把我当成亲生儿子
I'm also not
我也根本就不是
your elder brother.
你的哥哥
It was all because of Li Ni.
都是因为李嶷
If Li Ni hadn't existed,
如果没有李嶷的话
you would've been married to me already.
你早就嫁给我了
You also wouldn't have said
你也绝不会说出
something so ruthless!
如此冷酷无情的话
Whether there was Li Ni or not, I wouldn't fall in love with you.
有没有李嶷
Father has asked me a few times
父亲曾经
whether I want to be married to you.
想不想嫁给你
He felt that
他觉得你我
since we grew up together,
从小一起长大
you've been caring for me in every aspect.
你处处照顾我
He was thinking
阿爹在想
if he passed away
如果有一天
one day,
他离开了这个人世间
would I be lonely
留着我一个人
when I was left all alone?
会不会孤独
If you could take care of me,
如果有你来照顾我
he might not need to worry.
他或许可以放心
However, I told him
但是我告诉阿爹
that I won't be married to you,
我是不会嫁给你的
or perhaps
或者说那个时候
I didn't intend
我也没有打算
to get married at all.
嫁给任何人
However, you submitted a report to the emperor
可是你却向皇帝上书
that you wish to marry
要从三个皇子当中
one of the three princes.
选一个嫁
You're lying.
你骗我
It's not that you don't want to get married at all.
你根本就不是不想嫁人
You don't want to marry me at all.
你是根本就不想嫁给我
There's no need for me to lie to you.
我没有必要骗你
At one point, I really didn't have the intention to get married.
有一度我确实不想嫁人
A female has to face so many difficulties.
世间女子如此苦
I only live once.
来这世上走一遭
If no one understands me and knows me well,
如果没有人懂我知我
why must I be married to someone?
我为什么非要嫁人
Can't I live happily and freely alone?
我自己一个人
Do I not understand you
我难道不懂你
and know you well?
不知你吗
You used to respect me
你从前对我很尊重
and treat me well,
你也对我很好
but that was neither understanding me
但是那不是懂我
nor knowing me well.
也不是知我
Before I met Li Ni,
在遇到李嶷之前
I thought
我觉得
it's fine to be alone,
自己一个人挺好的
but after I met him,
但是遇到李嶷之后
I only want to be with him.
我只想跟他在一起
Ying.
阿萤
My love for you
我喜欢你
has already reached this extent.
都喜欢成那样了
Why did you say something like this to hurt me?
你为什么说这些话
Is it because
是不是因为
I'm associated with the Jieshuo people?
我跟揭硕人结交
Are you mad because of that?
所以你才特别生气
Do you hate me?
才特别恨我
I just want to survive.
我只是想要活下去
If I die,
如果我死了
will you remember me?
你会记得我吗
You won't!
你不会
You'll forget about me immediately!
你会马上把我给忘了
You'll put everything about me behind you!
你会把我抛诸脑后
You'll marry Li Ni
你会嫁给李嶷
and live happily ever after!
然后过着
You'll forget about me forever.
你会永远忘了我的
Therefore, I mustn't die.
所以我不能死
I mustn't die!
我不能死
I cannot allow you to marry Li Ni.
我不能让你嫁给李嶷
That's why I approached the Jieshuo people.
所以我才去找了揭硕人
Young Master.
公子
This might be the last time
这也许是我最后一次
I'm calling you this.
再叫你公子了
It's because the elder brother who used to care for me
因为从前那个爱护我
and deserved my respect
让我尊敬的兄长
is dead.
他已经死了
He is dead.
他死了
He died in that river.
他死在那条河里了
Of course, you have the right
你当然有权利
to choose to survive,
选择继续活下去
but you approached the Jieshuo people for your survival.
但你为了活着
You cannot say
你不能说
that it was all for me!
是为了我去找他们
After all is said,
说来说去
now everything...
如今这一切
seems to be
变成我自己
all my fault.
一个人的错了
Ying.
阿萤
How cruel you are.
你好狠的心哪
I've done so much for you,
我为你做了这么多
but now you make it sound like I have only myself to blame.
现在反倒是我咎由自取
To you,
你的眼里
you see no one other than Li Ni!
除了李嶷没有任何人
Anyway, it's all right, Ying.
不过没关系 阿萤
No matter what you say,
不论你怎么说
you'll never
这辈子
get to see Li Ni anymore in your entire life.
你都别想再见到李嶷了
I won't
我不会让他
let him take you away from me.
把你从我身边抢走
You'll surely become my wife.
你一定会是我的妻子
In your dreams!
你做梦
Never will I marry you!
我是绝对不会嫁给你的
Not only Li Ni, but also my father and his men
不止李嶷
will come and rescue me.
都会来救我的
You won't get away from this.
你是逃不掉的
The Cui Army has numerous cavalrymen.
崔家军有无数重骑
You've seen with your own eyes
你也曾经亲眼目睹过
how the Cui Army's cavalrymen charge.
崔家军的重骑
My father
我阿爹
will ride a horse here
会亲自纵着马过来
and crush your bones.
踏碎你的骨头
Mister Shiqi.
十七郎
Bao is ready.
老鲍那边准备好了
Just wait for them to take the bait.
就等上钩了
Get ready.
做好准备
Yes.
是
- Yes.
是 是 是
Young Master,
公子
the rangers sent a message.
游骑来报
At a hundred li away,
百余里外
they saw traces of cavalrymen who might have passed by.
有重骑行军的痕迹
Great General might be approaching us with his cavalry.
大将军应该是
If he reaches here with his cavalry,
若是大将军
all the decorations we've put up will be useless.
我们在别苑的这些布置
Furthermore, the cavalry even have armored horses.
而且那些重骑
When faced with them, our strategy will not work.
我们的机关
They will reach here at the latest by tomorrow noon.
最迟明日午时
Young Master.
公子
Please take our men back to Jieshuo's territory first
你先带人
using the trail over the mountain.
先退回揭硕之地吧
I will stay here
我守在这里
as if you and Lieutenant He are still here.
就假装您和校尉
I will hold the Great General off.
我拖住大将军